David Dahl

SUMMARY

Long time HTML Superfan, python nerd and node.js enthusuast, I have worked in many industries as a developer, engineering manager, researcher and fundraiser - at micro and macro scales. I am a pragmatic engineer with many years experience working with the best and brightest in the software industry

WORK EXPERIENCE

IBM (Raleigh, NC)

Software Engineering Researcher, 2017 - present

- As a member of the Web Platform team, I architect and implement scalable tools to help IBM with web security, privacy, internal website tooling and web standards
- ► I am currently building systems with Python and Node

Advisory Software Engineer, 2016 - 2017

- ▶ I advised teams and wrote code for the IBM Marketplace
- ► The stack was largely node.js, React, NoSQL

SpiderOak (Chicago, IL)

Director, Crypton project, 2013 - 2016

- ▶ Directed an engineering team building a privacy framework for mobile devices
- ► Helped raise a round of funding to continue the Crypton project
- ▶ Wrote much of the code in the Crypton framework (Node.js, Postgres, redis, Socket.io)
- ▶ Built Kloak private social network application for iOS and Android

Mozilla Corp (Mountain View, CA)

Senior Software Engineer, Privacy, 2012 - 2013

- ▶ I worked on new and existing browser features and WebAPIs to increase user privacy and security
- ► Engineer on Firefox OS user privileges code
- ▶ I was focused on implementing *DOMCrypt* in Gecko/Firefox, which was an initial strawman proposal for the W3C Web Cryptography Working Group
- ► Implemented window.crypto.getRandomValues in Firefox

Firefox Engineer, 2009 - 2012

- ► Front-end Firefox browser features, developer tools, browser Identity
- ▶ Implemented the original Web Console developer tool:
- ▶ Web Console frontend and backend code

Industrial Light + Magic (San Francisco, CA)

Software Engineer, 2007 - 2008

▶ ILM training department. I built Python / Django / ffmpeg-based tools for training artists, software engineers and other technical staff at ILM, LucasArts, Lucas Animation and Lucasfilm with a userbase of 1000

EDUCATION

I am a self-taught engineer

I have many mentors to be thankful for

SKILLS

Very experienced with Linux, Python, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, C++
Node, Express, npm, yarn, webpack, React, Django
Postgresql (including replication), MySQL, SQLite, Redis, CouchDB / Cloudant
Raspberry Pi, hardware sensors, etc
Evaluating and making recommendations for software/technology, tech teams, business processes

TALKS / WRITING / TEACHING

Defcon 23: Crypto Village: Anti-social Networking

- ► A talk on the Kloak application I created at SpiderOak that functions like Twitter but is end to end encrypted
- ► https://bit.ly/2JoSNbu

Future Insights Live: Privacy is a UX Problem

- ▶ Privacy is not simply a technical issue. More designers are needed to solve privacy applicaiton issues
- ► https://bit.ly/2Jr80Jd

Hack in the Box Malaysia: Crypton Workshop

- ► https://bit.ly/2JaB2JC
- ▶ Live-codoing workshop on Crypton

Crypton Whitepaper

- ► Crypton paper produced for Hack In The Box conference
- ► https://bit.ly/2Jbubjg

LINKS

Website

► https://txt.ist

Github

► https://github.com/daviddahl/